Edwin Diamond Political Audiovisual Collection
Edwin Diamond Political Audiovisual Collection
1960-1996
Diamond, Edwin.
83 linear ft.
Recordings of political advertisements, television commercials, televised political debates and coverage of Republican and Democratic Party conventions; also research material for book The Spot (1992), co-authored with Stephen Bates
2606156
Biographical History
Edwin Diamond, journalist, author and professor, began his journalistic career as a science writer with the International News Service in Chicago. He joined Newsweek in 1957 and was named a senior editor in 1962. He was on-air commentator for the Washington Post Co., editorial director of Adweek, cofounder of the Washington Journalism Review, associate editor of the New York Daily News, and a media columnist for New York magazine for 10 years. In addition to his media work, Diamond was a visiting professor of political science at MIT and then at New York University and the author of a dozen books, and won numerous awards for writing, editing, and classroom teaching, as well as a 1994 Professional Achievement Award from the University of Chicago's Alumni Association.
Diamond was a veteran of both World War II and Korea, and received a Bronze Star and a Purple Heart during his military service. He and his wife, Adelina Lust Diamond, had three daughters.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Edwin Diamond Political Audiovisual Collection contains research material for The Spot (1992), co-authored with Stephen Bates, and a wide range of audiovisual recordings.
"The Spot" material contains information amassed during the research and writing of the 1992 book co-authored by Diamond and attorney Stephen Bates. The bulk of this series consists of audiorecordings and notes of interviews with individuals connected with political consulting and advertising, including Roger Ailes, John Deardourff, Eddie Mahe, Dan Payne, Gerald Rafshoon, and Stu Spencer.
Tapes and Films contain politically-related recordings on various forms of videotape and audiotape, and 16mm film. Content includes coverage of Republican and Democratic Party conventions, political advertisements (most of which were aired as television commercials), televised political debates, candidate or issue spots, interviews, press conferences, documentaries, and news broadcasts. Most items date from the 1960s to the 1990s; topics covered include busing, the Iranian hostage crisis, AIDS, advertising that targets children, John F. Kennedy, the arms race, housing, drug abuse, US relations with Russia, China, Japan and other foreign powers, and the role of media in the democratic process. The collection also includes several reels of film coverage of the Young Republican National Convention in San Francisco (1963), an event that is marked as formative to the ascendacy of Barry Goldwater to the Republican nomination for the 1964 presidential campaign.
Arrangement of the Collection
Items are boxed in numeric order.
Related Material
has a number of collections relating to television and radio. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Politics, government and public administration; Radio, television, film; Bates, Stephen, 1958-; Diamond, Edwin.; Advertising, Political -- United States.; Television in politics -- United States.; Television broadcasting of news -- United States.; 16mm (photographic film size); Audiocassettes.; Audiotapes.; Videotapes.; Beta (Betamax); Sound recordings.; U-matic.; VHS.; Video recordings (physical artifacts); Television journalists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Access to recordings requires advance notice to produce a working copy.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Edwin Diamond.
"The Spot" material, gift of Stephen Bates, 2019.
Inventory
- "The Spot" material
  Gift of co-author Stephen Bates, 2019.
  - Interviews
    - Deardourff, John [tape 1 of 2], 5/10/1983; diamond_e_021; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 51)
    - Deardourff, John [tape 2 of 2]; Guggenheim, Charles, 5/10/1983; 5/11/1983; diamond_e_022; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Box 51)
    - Goodman, [Isaac] Robert, 7/25/1983; diamond_e_025; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 51)
    - Goodman, [Isaac] Robert; Gans, Curtis; Bond, Becky; Dooley, Ed, 7/27/1983; diamond_e_026; label reads: "last of Goodman; spots; Committee for the Study of the American Electorate; NCTA"; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 51)
    - Kaye, Michael, 5/31/1983; diamond_e_023; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 51)
    - Kopelman, Arie L.; Squier, Robert, 7/22/1983; 7/27/1983; diamond_e_024; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 51)
    - MacDougall, Malcolm, diamond_e_017; label reads: "NYC"; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 51)
    - Mahe, Eddie; Guggenheim Spots, diamond_e_020; Robert F. Kennedy Presidential '68.; George McGovern Presidential '72; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 51)
    - Payne, Dan, 4/14/1983; diamond_e_018; label reads: " CX; MIT [Massachusetts Institute of Technology], media expert"; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 51)
    - Payne, Dan, 10/2/1987; diamond_e_028; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 51)
    - Rafshoon, Gerald; Squier, Robert, diamond_e_019; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 51)
    - Sawyer, David H., 8/8/1983; diamond_e_027; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Box 51)
    - Swope, Ken; Payne, Dan, 1/22/1988; 01/25/1988; diamond_e_029; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 51)
    - Swope, Ken, 4/7/1983; diamond_e_016; label reads: "Class/ CX"; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 51)
  - Notes
    - Ailes, Roger (Box 52)
    - Deardourff, John (Box 52)
    - Dooley, Ed (Box 52)
    - Florescu, John (Box 52)
    - Foster, James (Box 52)
    - Garth, David (Box 52)
    - Goodman, Robert (Box 52)
    - Kaye, Michael (Box 52)
    - Litsky, Andy (Box 52)
    - Mahe, Eddie (Box 52)
    - Payne, Dan (Box 52)
    - Rafshoon, Gerald (Box 52)
    - Schwartz, Tony (Box 52)
    - Spencer, Stu (Box 52)
    - Squier, Robert (Box 52)
    - Swope, Ken (Box 52)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Photograph
    - Radio Dialogue: "On the Spot", Bates, Stephen, 07/01/1992; diamond_e_030; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 28:48 (Box 51)
    - McGovern Election Eve Broadcast, aired Nov 6, 1972; diamond_e_031; VHS; running time 30:00 (Box 51)
    - Spots: JFK; Nixon; Taft; Buckley; Evans; Agnew; Stokes; Melvinski; Lindsay; A-Bomb (LBJ), Smith; NHH; McGovern, 5/21/1984; diamond_e_032; label reads: "HN 1742: 30 sec. man; S-ILM; X-fer"; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 51)
    - Electronic Democracy, Dec 13 1995; diamond_e_033; label reads: "WN#4547, EU#1241"; VHS; running time 60:00 (Box 51)
- Tapes D0001-D0299
  - D0001 Campaign Speech - Producer: 17.24 John B. Anderson (Box 1)
    3/4 inch videotape: U-matic
  - D0002 We Can Beat the White Machine - Producer: 17.24 Edward M. Weaver, John Krooss (Box 1)
  - D0003 60 minutes - News or Entertainment - Producer: 17.24 Monty Talley, Jay White, 12/12/79 (Box 1)
  - D0004 Television and the Church: Differing Views - Producer: 17.255 Media Project: Michael Schlein, Bob Wallace (Box 1)
  - D0005 Shot Down Over Nicaragua - Producer: 60 Minutes, 10/19/86 (Box 1)
  - D0006 [no title] - Producer: ABC/CBS, 6/19/76 - 12/11/75 (Box 1)
  - D0007 Carter Energy Address - Producer: ABC, 4/20/77 (Box 1)
  - D0008 Carter Energy Address to Congress and Analysis - Producer: ABC, 4/20/77 (Box 1)
  - D0009 Nielson Ratings - Producer: ABC/NBC, 11/7 - 9/77; Vanderbilt TV News Archive
  - D0010 Captioned News - Producer: ABC, 4/25/79 (Box 1)
  - D0011 News - Carter - Brezhnev - Summit: Arms and the Future - Producer: ABC, 6/17/79 (Box 1)
  - D0012 News - Barbara Walters Interviews Jimmy Carter - Producer: ABC, 10/9/79 (Box 1)
  - D0013 World News - Producer: ABC, 10/9/80; 10/27-28/80 (Box 1)
  - D0014 News - Nightline Tape 1 - Producer: ABC, 11/5/80 (Box 1)
  - D0015 News - Nightline Tape 2 - Producer: ABC, 11/5/80 (Box 1)
  - D0016 News - Nightline - History - Producer: ABC, 5/29/81 (Box 1)
  - D0017 America Held Hostage - Producer: ABC, 11/1/81 (Box 1)
  - D0018 Evening News / World News Tonite / Late Night News - Producer: ABC/CBS, 10/21 - 22/81; 4/2/82 (Box 2)
  - D0019 Viewpoint (Minus 1st 5 min) - Producer: ABC, 4/28/82 (Box 2)
  - D0020 Viewpoint (Part 11 - third half hour) - Producer: ABC, 4/29/82 (Box 2)
  - D0021 Good Morning America - T.V. Guide Monitoring Project - Producer: ABC, 2/22/83 (Box 2)
  - D0022 Early Morning - Producer: ABC, 3/24/83 (Box 2)
  - D0023 Viewpoint - Day After #1 - Producer: ABC, 11/20/83 (Box 2)
  - D0024 Viewpoint - Day After #2 - Producer: ABC, 11/20/83 (Box 2)
  - D0025 Viewpoint - Day After #3 - Producer: ABC, 11/20/83 (Box 2)
  - D0026 Viewpoint - Day After #4 - Producer: ABC, 11/20/83 (Box 2)
  - D0027 20/20 - 30 sec.: Mon - Producer: ABC, 5/21/84 (Box 2)
  - D0028 20/20 NM 517 - Producer: ABC, 5/21/84 (Box 2)
  - D0029 News - 20/20 - 30 Second Man - Producer: ABC, 5/21/84 (Box 2)
  - D0030 Thirty Second Man - Producer: ABC, 5/21/84 (Box 2)
  - D0031 20/20 - 30 sec. Man - History - Producer: ABC, 9/12/84 (Box 2)
  - D0032 Nightline Pt 1 & 2 - Producer: ABC, 3/18/85 (Box 2)
  - D0033 20/20 History - Producer: ABC, 1/8/87 (Box 2)
  - D0034 Mon. - Producer: ABC, no sound? (Box 2)
  - D0035 Dukakis - Bush - Producer: Ad Bank (Box 3)
  - D0036 Issue #5 Marketing High Tech - Producer: AdVideo Journal, 1984 (Box 3)
  - D0037 Best and Worst Ads for '82 - Producer: AdWeek, 1982 (Box 3)
  - D0038 Reports - Adweek Master #6 - Producer: AdWeek (Box 3)
  - D0039 A Countdown 1) New Charlie/Old Charlie, 2) Advt. To Women Harvey's Bristol Creme, 3) New Wisk/Old Wisk, 4) Diet Pepsi - Producer: AdWeek (Box 3)
  - D0040 Mitch McConnell Spots (13 Spots) - Producer: Ailes Communications (Box 3)
  - D0041 AIDS Awareness: "Rumors" - (With one each of) Elizabeth McGovern (Sex), Wayne Rogers, Ahmad Rashad, Glenn Close, Johnny Carson, Sam Waterston, Meryl Streep, Robert DeNiro - Producer: American Red Cross, 5/6/87 (Box 3)
  - D0042 Countdown for America (Peace Poll Version) - Producer: American Security Council Foundation (Box 3)
  - D0043 Shaping the Computer Age - Producer: AT&T, 3/27/84 (Box 3)
  - D0044 Rolling Stones - Emotional Rescue, She's So Cold, Where the Boys Go - Producer: Atlantic Records, 10/1/80 (Box 3)
  - D0045 Glenn Ford as Spokesman for AVIS - Producer: AVIS Rent a Car (Box 3)
  - D0046 Glenn Ford as Spokesman for AVIS - Producer: AVIS Rent a Car (Box 3)
  - D0047 Simon for President: The Paul Simon Story - Producer: Axelrod & Associates (Box 3)
  - D0048 Hyundai Motor America - Ship, Locomotive, Canada, College, Baby, Both Excels, Pleasant Journey, Excelebration, Rear Defroster - Producer: Backer & Spielvogel (Box 3)
  - D0049 Miller Lite Beer: Yakov Smirnoff - Producer: Backer & Spielvogel (Box 3)
  - D0050 Miller/Meisterbrau: Royal Order of the Bison - Producer: Backer & Spielvogel (Box 3)
  - D0051 Bernice Kanner - NY Magazine - Producer: Botten, Barton, Durstine, Osborn, 1/12/87 (Box 4)
  - D0052 Denise Program - Producer: Boston Broadcasting Inc. (Box 4)
  - D0053 Interviews with David Frost / AIG Commercials - Opening, Pyramid, Clocks, Closing - Producer: Bozell, Jacobs, Kenyon & Eckhardt (Box 4)
  - D0054 Nixon: Checkers to Watergate - Producer: Braverman Productions (Box 4)
  - D0055 Chicago Ads (Washington Commercials Dubbed for WNEV Boston) - Producer: Byrne, Daley, 1993 (Box 4)
  - D0056 Video Encyclopedia of the 20th Century - Producer: C.E.L. Educational Resources, 1/15/86 (Box 4)
  - D0057 The Juggler of Notre Dame - with short Blocks - Producer: Capital Cities Family Special (Box 4)
  - D0058 Election Coverage - Producer: CBS - WBZ - WCVB, 11/2/76 (Box 4)
  - D0059 Election Night - Producer: CBS, 11/2/76 (Box 4)
  - D0060 Election Night Coverage - Producer: CBS, 11/2/76 (Box 4)
  - D0061 Election Night Coverage - Producer: CBS, 11/2/76 (Box 4)
  - D0062 Bert Lance Evening News 8/8 - - Producer: CBS/NBC, 9/6/77; 8/8 - 9/14/77; Vanderbilt TV News Archive (Box 4)
  - D0063 1978 Election Results Massachusetts (1 of 3) - Producer: CBS, 10/8/78 (Box 4)
  - D0064 1978 Election Results - Massachusetts and U.S. - 2 of 3 - Producer: CBS, 11/8/78 (Box 4)
  - D0065 Reports - The Boat People / Miami: The Trial that Sparked the Riots /The Boston Goes to China - Producer: CBS, 1/16/79; 4/20/79,; 8/27/80 (Box 4)
  - D0066 Reports - Danger at 3 Mile Island - Producer: CBS, 3/30/79 (Box 5)
  - D0067 News - Roger Mudd on Commercials - Producer: CBS, 2/21/80 (Box 5)
  - D0068 Prima Coverage - South Carolina Republican Primary - Producer: CBS, 3/8/80 (Box 5)
  - D0069 Primary Coverage in Florida, Georgia & Alabama - Part I - Producer: CBS (Box 5)
  - D0070 Primary Coverage - Part II - Producer: CBS, 3/11/80 - 3/25/80 - 4/1/80 (Box 5)
  - D0071 Primary Coverage - Special Attn. To the Chicago Daley Machine - Producer: CBS, 3/18/80 (Box 5)
  - D0072 Primary Coverage in NY & CN - Part 1 of 2 - Producer: CBS, 3/25/80 (Box 5)
  - D0073 Primary Coverage in Kansas & Wisconsin - Part 1 of 2 - Producer: CBS, 4/1/80 (Box 5)
  - D0074 Primary Coverage - Pennsylvania, Vermont, Missouri - Part 1 of II - Producer: CBS, 4/22/80 (Box 5)
  - D0075 Evening News - Aborted Iran Rescue Mission of Hostages - Producer: CBS, 4/25/80 (Box 5)
  - D0076 H. Brown Press Conference / Iran Rescue Mission Post Mortem - Producer: CBS, 4/25/80 (Box 5)
  - D0077 Primary Coverage - Producer: CBS, 5/6/80 (Box 5)
  - D0078 Newsbreak - Ch. 7 Boston Primary Report - Producer: CBS, 5/6 - 13/80 (Box 5)
  - D0079 Primary Coverage - Maryland & Nebraska / Primary Coverage in Penn., VT & MO - Producer: CBS, 4/22/80; 5/13/80 (Box 5)
  - D0080 Cronkite, Carter, Kennedy / Super Tuesday Coverage - CA, SD, RI, NJ, WV, NM, OH, MN - Producer: CBS, 6/3/80 (Box 5)
  - D0081 Reports - Sale Presentation - Producer: CBS, 7/22/80 (Box 5)
  - D0082 Evening News - Campaign '80 Coverage - Producer: CBS, 10/27 - 11/3/80 (Box 5)
  - D0083 Evening News - Campaign '80 Coverage - Producer: CBS, 10/27 - 11/3/80 (Box 5)
  - D0084 News - Special Report - Election Preview - Producer: CBS, 11/3/80 (Box 5)
  - D0085 Political Ads - Ron Reagan, John Anderson - Producer: CBS, 11/3/80 (Box 5)
  - D0086 Election Night Coverage 7 - 9PM - Producer: CBS, 11/4/80 (Box 5)
  - D0087 Election Night Coverage 9 - 11PM - Producer: CBS, 11/4/80 (Box 6)
  - D0088 Ronald Reagan Press Conference - Producer: CBS, 11/6/80 (Box 6)
  - D0089 Nicaraguan Aerial, Recon Photos - Producer: CBS, 3/9 - 10/82 - 5/19/82; Vanderbilt TV News Archive (Box 6)
  - D0090 Nightly News John Chancellor Signs Off / Evening News - Producer: CBS/NBC, 4/2/82 (Box 6)
  - D0091 Morning News #1 7 - 8AM - Producer: CBS, 2/11/83; 2/22/83 (Box 6)
  - D0092 Morning News #2 8 - 9 AM - Producer: CBS, 2/11/83; 2/22/83 (Box 6)
  - D0093 AM - Back up - Producer: CBS, 2/23/83 (Box 6)
  - D0094 AM Back u - Producer: CBS, 2/23/83 (Box 6)
  - D0095 Early Morning News - Producer: CBS, 3/27/83 (Box 6)
  - D0096 Nightwatch - Producer: CBS, 4/29/83 (Box 6)
  - D0097 For Our Times - Nuclear Arms & Religious Conscience - Producer: CBS, 5/15/83 (Box 6)
  - D0098 News - Comiso Report - Soviet Militarism - 10 minute interviews - Producer: CBS, 2/19/85 - 12/-/82[5?] (Box 6)
  - D0099 Channel 2 News at 5 - Heart of the Matter - Producer: CBS, 3/26/85 (Box 6)
  - D0100 Morning News - Producer: CBS, 5/8/85 (Box 6)
  - D0101 Morning News - Producer: CBS, 5/8/85 (Box 6)
  - D0102 Evening News - Willie Horton Ad. - Eric Engberg - Producer: CBS, 10/14/92 (Box 6)
  - D0103 Morning News From Europe - Producer: CBS, 5/7/?? (Box 6)
  - D0104 Morning News From Europe - Producer: CBS, 5/7/?? (Box 7)
  - D0105 News - Sunday AM - "Inherently Unequal" - Producer: CBS, 9/13 - 20/?? (Box 7)
  - D0106 Evening News - Producer: CBS/NBC, 10/1 - 7/?? (Box 7)
  - D0107 Jerry Cohen - CSX Corp. - Single System Service - Producer: CBS/NBC (Box 7)
  - D0108 AM #1 Monday - Producer: CBS (Box 7)
  - D0109 AM #2 Monday 8 - 9AM - Producer: CBS (Box 7)
  - D0110 Fire [War] From the Sky - Reel 1 of 2 - Producer: CBS (Box 7)
  - D0111 Fire [War] From the Sky - Reel 2 of 2 - Producer: CBS (Box 7)
  - D0112 News - Israel has Nuclear Bombs - Producer: CBS (Box 7)
  - D0113 Tet - Producer: CBS (Box 7)
  - D0114 Under Fire - Producer: CBS (Box 7)
  - D0115 YSL Sport - Pieces White Group - Producer: CDL (Box 7)
  - D0116 Federal Elections '78 - Producer: Ch. 44 Boston, 11/5/78 (Box 7)
  - D0117 Vietnam Legacy: A Shattered Silence - Producer: Ch. 5 - Nightshift, 1/11/82 (Box 7)
  - D0118 Ed Diamond and Barbara Anderson on Morality in Media - Producer: Ch. 5 Local (Box 7)
  - D0119 Election Night Local News - Producer: Ch 7, 11/4/80 (Box 7)
  - D0120 1978 Election Results - Massachusetts - Producer: Ch 7 Boston, 10/8/78 (Box 7)
  - D0121 The Howie Carr Style - Producer: Ch 7 Boston (Box 8)
  - D0122 Eyewitness News - Newspaper War - Producer: Ch. 7 NY, 11/10/80 (Box 8)
  - D0123 700 Club 3 Excerpts - Producer: Christian Broadcasting Network (Box 8)
  - D0124 In the Wake of Watergate, Carter Wins His Mace In History - Producer: Class Project - Susan Kerr, Jack Krooss (Box 8)
  - D0125 Televangelism Special - Producer: CNN, 8/22/81 (Box 8)
  - D0126 9 - 9PM - Producer: CNN, 3/11/83 (Box 8)
  - D0127 9 - 10PM - Producer: CNN, 3/11/83 (Box 8)
  - D0128 1984 N.H. Debate Ted Koppel Moderates 1st 90min. 8 Democratic Primary Candidates - Producer: CNN, 1/15/84 (Box 8)
  - D0129 History of TV - For John "Showbiz" Rhodes - Producer: CNN, 5/2/?? (Box 8)
  - D0130 Fireworks - Sidewalk Snack Bar - Block Party - Hottest Day Hobie Cat - Producer: Coca Cola (Box 8)
  - D0131 Soccermania - Tape number 2 - Producer: Coca Cola (Box 8)
  - D0132 1980 Carter Commercials Reel #1 - Producer: D. Garcia, 5/7/81 (Box 8)
  - D0133 1980 Carter Commercials Reel #3 - Producer: D. Garcia, 5/7/81 (Box 8)
  - D0134 1980 Carter Commercials Reel #5 - Producer: D. Garcia, 5/8/81 (Box 8)
  - D0135 John Glenn - 1 Spot / Kevin White - 7 Spots / Ted Kennedy - 2 Spots - Producer: D.H. Sawyer & Associates (Box 8)
  - D0136 Blue Bell - Wrangler - Bucking Horse/No Slap, Stagecoach, Stampede, Rodeo - Producer: Dancer, Fitzgerald & Sample Inc. (Box 9)
  - D0137 Wendy's: Russian Fashion Show - Producer: Dancer, Fitzgerald & Sample Inc. (Box 9)
  - D0138 Senior Citizens, Farmers, Past Performance, Ed Davis, Taxi, Rape, Fact, Shopping Center - Producer: Deukmejain for Governor (Box 9)
  - D0139 Believe in the Future Again - Producer: DH Sawyer - Glenn for President, 10/13/83 (Box 9)
  - D0140 Reagan/Mondale - Hunt/Helms - Producer: DH Sawyer & Associates (Box 9)
  - D0141 Civil Defense in Case of Nuclear War - Producer: Documentary Guild (Box 9)
  - D0142 H.H.H. Weather Vane - Producer: Doyle, Dane, Bernbach Inc., 9/29/83 (Box 9)
  - D0143 New Era, Hey Pal, Plant Closing, Taking Charge, Results, That's for Sure - Producer: Dukakis for President (Box 9)
  - D0144 TV Finest Hours - Producer: Entertainment Tonight (Box 9)
  - D0145 Heart of the Dragon: Episode 2 - Producer: Goodman/Comora (Box 9)
  - D0146 Heart of the Dragon Episode 1 - Producer: Goodman/Comora (Box 9)
  - D0147 Sales Demo Reel - Producer: GSA (Box 9)
  - D0148 Agency Presentation Reel - 27 spots - Producer: Hal Riney & Partners Inc., 10/20/86 (Box 9)
  - D0149 Advertising Agency Presentation Reel - Producer: Hal Riney & Partners, 3/23/88 (Box 9)
  - D0150 #104 The Press at Your Door (Invasion of Privacy) - Producer: Inside Story, 5/26/81 (Box 9)
  - D0151 The Press and the Public Project - The Eye of the Beholder - Producer: Inside Story, 12/4/81 (Box 9)
  - D0152 #201 - Chicago to New York: Drop Dead - Producer: Inside Story (Box 9)
  - D0153 #204 Poland: The News in Uniform - Producer: Inside Story (Box 10)
  - D0154 L#205 - Once is Enough - Producer: Inside Story (Box 10)
  - D0155 #209 - El Salvador - Part 1 - Producer: Inside Story (Box 10)
  - D0156 #210 El Salvador Part 1 - Producer: Inside Story (Box 10)
  - D0157 #210 EI Salvador Part 2 - Producer: Inside Story (Box 10)
  - D0158 #211 The Numbers Game - Producer: Inside Story (Box 10)
  - D0159 #209 Inside El Salvador Part One - Producer: Inside Story, 7/2/82; On Case - #213 Middle East Image: Is There a Tilt? 4/30/1982 (Box 10)
  - D0160 #312 Scandals at the Checkout Counter - Producer: Inside Story, 6/21/83 (Box 10)
  - D0161 Oxford Debate - Producer: Inside Story, 2/27/84 (Box 10)
  - D0162 Payne Demo Reel / Goodman Demo Reel - Producer: Institute of Politics (Box 10)
  - D0163 Floyd Haskel - Spots 6 - 10 - Producer: Interface (Box 10)
  - D0164 Political spots - Bush, Dole, Baker / Iowa Press on the Precinct Caucuses - Producer: Iowa Public Broadcasting Record, 1/20/80 (Box 10)
  - D0165 Candidate Spots - Connally, Carter, Crane - Producer: Iowa Public Broadcasting Record (Box 10)
  - D0166 Burger King: Three Stooges - Producer: J. Walters Thompson USA (Box 10)
  - D0167 Pete Wilson for Senate - 2 Spots / Deukmeijian for Governor - 6 Spots - Producer: Jack Link, 10/21/82 (Box 10)
  - D0168 An Assessment of the Media Coverage of the Report of the President's Commission on the Accident at Three Mile Island - Producer: Jean Wisner / Lawrence Loomis / Darren DePoy (Box 10)
  - D0169 News Conference - Jerry Brown - Producer: KNBC (Box 11)
  - D0170 Carter Spot / Reagan Show / Ford - Carter Ads - Producer: KNXT / KHJ - TV, 6/4/76 (Box 11)
  - D0171 Penna. Primary (Political Spots that Have Been Aired) - Producer: KYW - TV, 4/1/80 (Box 11)
  - D0172 Time Man of the Year - Producer: LBS Communications, 1/3/86 (Box 11)
  - D0173 Nebraska - Moonshine - Bubble Things - Producer: Lord, Geller, Federico, Einstein, Inc. - The New Yorker, 10/18/85 (Box 11)
  - D0174 Presidential Candidates 1956 - 1964 - Producer: Lyndon Baines Johnson Library, 9/28/76 (Box 11)
  - D0175 British Television Advertising Awards - Final Judging Session #1 - Producer: McCann - Erickson Advertising, 8/27/84 (Box 11)
  - D0176 Coca - Cola USA - Growing Up/Lyric/Dialogue, First Job, 10K, License, Uniform, Hero - Producer: McCann - Erickson Advertising (Box 11)
  - D0177 Nobody Can Do It Like You Can - Producer: McDonald's Communications TVT 31-33, 1979 (Box 11)
  - D0178 Volkswagen - 11 spots - Producer: MGS Services, 11/30/83 (Box 11)
  - D0179 Profits: Think About It - Producer: Mobil Corp. Advertisement, 11/21/80 (Box 11)
  - D0180 Fables: Pilobolus, Misunderstood Elephant, Shields and Yarnell, Squirrel, Kinestatis, Procrastinating Lion - Producer: Mobil Corp. Advertisement (Box 11)
  - D0181 Russia Rev. - Business Shift Rev. - Revolutionary Rev. - Fanatic Rev. - Producer: MTV Network, 12/30/85 (Box 11)
  - D0182 Breakfast with Billie Jean - Producer: MTV Network's VH-1 (Box 11)
  - D0183 Geography, Science, Band 2, Homeroom - Producer: National Education Association (Box 11)
  - D0184 1980 Republican National Advertising Campaign - Producer: National Republican Congressional Committee (Box 11)
  - D0185 Network - Part 1 - Producer: National Video Center (Box 11)
  - D0186 Child Abuse, Monique L. - Producer: TBWA, 1/29/87 (Box 12)
  - D0187 First 4 News, 5:30PM - Producer: WBZ, 2/3/77 (Box 12)
  - D0188 Busing Media Coverage - Producer: NBC, 9/8/75 (Box 12)
  - D0189 News - 2d Ford Carter Debate Tape II / Analysis of Debate - Producer: NBC, 10/6/76 (Box 12)
  - D0190 Dole - Mondale Debate & NBC Analysis Part II - Producer: NBC, 10/15/76 (Box 12)
  - D0191 Dole - Mondale Debate & NBC Analysis Part II - Producer: NBC, 10/15/76 (Box 12)
  - D0192 3rd debate - Ford, Carter - Tape 1 - Producer: NBC, 10/22/76 (Box 12)
  - D0193 A Day With President Carter - Producer: NBC, 4/14/77 (Box 12)